## **JULIE SCHER**

(239) 321-9752

ABAintheGTA.com

# **Profile Summary**

Ethical and results-driven Ontario Autism Program (OAP) approved Board Certified Behavior Analyst (BCBA) with over 10 years of clinical experience in the field of Applied Behaviour Analysis (ABA). Highly experienced administering various assessment tools, creating skill acquisition programs, writing individualized behaviour intervention plans, and making data-based decisions.

#### **CORE SKILLS & COMPETENCIES**

- Data & Treatment Analysis
- Supervision & Mentorship
- Documentation & Handling
- Treatment Planning
- Skill Building
- Assessment Administration
- Data-based decision making
- Team Collaboration

#### FORMAL EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Applied Behaviour Analysis (Honors) | Ball State University | Muncie, IN

June. 2015

- ✓ Earned two graduate certificates in Autism and Applied Behaviour Analysis.
- Awarded the Dean's Citation for Academic Excellence in recognition a perfect 4.0 GPA.

Relevant Coursework: Interventions and Treatments for Persons with Autism | Research Methods

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (Specialized Honors) | York University | Toronto, ON

June. 2009

Recipient of the Vanier Vingt-Deux Award: The Master's Honor Roll.

Relevant Coursework: Developmental Psych. | Abnormal Psych. | Advanced Statistical Methods

Bachelor of Arts, Radio and Television Arts (Honors) | Ryerson University | Toronto, ON

June. 2004

- Among the top 15% of students for academic achievement
- Member of the Golden Key International Honor Society

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Owner/Clinical Director | ABA in the GTA Autism Behaviour Therapy (formerly ABA Supervisors) | Toronto, ON April 2016 – Present

Provide consultation to clients and families in need treatment, resource support, and education within the field of ABA. Create individualized treatment programs using empirically validated and evidence-based methods. Offer feedback to consumers and therapists on treatment execution using interobserver agreement data to ensure high treatment fidelity.

✓ Notably established the business from the ground up, progressively increasing revenue and retaining an extremely high client satisfaction rate.

Lead a team in facilitating optimal care and and measurable positive outcomes for clients with autism and other developmental disabilities. Designed and evaluated individualized academic skill acquisition programs and behaviour protocols. Executed parent training.

✓ Provided expert hiring, BST training, supervision, and clinical oversight to over 17 staff.

# BCBA | Speech Therapy Works | Toronto, ON

October 2017 – January 2018

Oversaw clinical team meetings and problem solved with a multidisciplinary team of professionals. Motivated and trained a team of instructor therapists on evidence-based practices and techniques.

✓ Delivered consultation services to assist in the launch of the new ABA department.

## Instructor Therapist | Above and Beyond Consulting | Toronto, ON

September 2015 - April 2016

Implemented academic and skill acquisition programs with high treatment integrity. Delivered behaviour support plan protocols as designed.

Instructor Therapist | <u>Under the Umbrella Tree Educational Services Inc.</u> | Toronto, ON

September 2015 – April 2016

Conducted ABLLS-R and VB-MAPP assessments. Interpreted and presented client data at clinical team meetings. Provided short-term, volunteer, assistance to the BCBA on staff.

### Instructor Therapist | Blue Balloon Health Services | Toronto, ON

November 2012 – January 2014

Wrote behaviour protocols to decrease problem behaviour and increase appropriate responses under the supervision of a BCBA. Graphed data and monitored client progress. Accrued independent volunteer fieldwork hours by providing DTT and NET practices to learners with ASD.

### **AREAS OF PROVEN PERFORMANCE**

- Treatment Planning: Expert ability to design and analyze evidence-based academic skill acquisition programs and behaviour support plans to maximize success.
- **Training & Mentorship:** Highly capable of working with clients, families, community partners, and interdisciplinary teams to provide quality supervision on treatment implementation.
- Data Analysis: Skilled in developing, implementing, analyzing, and interpreting the results of functional analyses and functional behavioural assessments.
- **Skill Building:** Proven capacity to reduce maladaptive behaviour and increase socially valid behaviours for individuals with autism, and other developmental challenges.

# **TECHNICAL ACUMEN**